Ms. Shi!
石小姐
We're old friends.
老朋友了
We just met
我们不久前
not long ago at the tailor shop.
刚在裁缝铺见过
Mr. Wei, is there
魏先生找我
something you need from me?
有什么事儿吗
I'm truly sorry
实在是不好意思
for disturbing you so late,
这么晚打搅你了
but there is a matter
的确有点儿事儿
that requires your cooperation
需要石小姐
for an investigation.
来配合调查一下
It's quite late today.
今天太晚了
Perhaps another time.
下一次吧
I apologize, Ms. Shi,
对不起 石小姐
but you know who I am
你应该知道我是什么人
and why I'm here.
我是来干什么的
Mr. Wei, it's very inconvenient for you
魏先生你这样不请自来
to come uninvited.
我很不方便
I'm not here to socialize,
我不是来做客的
Ms. Shi.
石小姐
No point in pretending.
就不跟你假客气了
As a member of the French Concession's
石小姐身为法租界
Council Police,
公董局的警务人员
you
应该不可能不知道
must be aware of
我们安琪啤酒公司
what A.G. Beer does?
是干什么的吧
If there's something you need,
如果你有什么事情
you can find me
明天可以到公董局
at the Council tomorrow.
找我谈
Sorry,
不好意思
it's not strictly official business.
也不完全是公事
Tsvetaeva?
茨维塔耶娃
Ms. Shi, you and I
我和石小姐
go way back.
算是相识甚早啊
I've
早在
made acquaintance with you
孟家的凶杀案的时候
since the Meng family murder case,
我俩就有交道
a peculiar connection indeed.
可谓是缘分不浅
Connect me
请帮我接一下
to the Central Patrol.
中央巡捕房
Apologies.
不好意思
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
Mrs. Ji from Zijin Tailor Shop
子衿裁缝铺的季太太
has been arrested,
已经被我们逮捕了
and that puts you in a difficult position, doesn't it?
你让我怎么看你
Just because I had clothes
就因为我在那儿
made there,
做过衣服
I'm a suspect?
所以我也有嫌疑
This dress, did Mrs. Ji make it as well?
这件也是季太太做的
Come,
走
take me downstairs.
带我去楼下
Let's take a look at your car.
看看你的车去
What's wrong with my car?
我的车有什么问题
Let's check it out
去看看不就知道
and see.
有什么问题了吗
I know all too well
我太清楚
what you did
你们抓共产党的时候
when arresting Communists.
是什么德行
Don't put on a show with me.
少在我面前装腔作势
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
when it comes to combating Communism,
在抓共产党的问题上
your Council
你们公董局
and our Reviving Society
和我们复兴社
stand side by side.
是一致的
So you wouldn't recline
所以你不会拒绝
a cooperation request, right?
配合我吧
Go downstairs
下楼
and show me your car.
看你的车
Here's my car.
这就是我的车
Want me to open
要不要把所有的门
the doors for you?
都给你打开
No need.
不用了
Apologies for the trouble.
不好意思啊
We were
我们在执行任务
pursuing a Communist,
抓一个共产党的时候
who was rescued by his accomplice
被他的共产党同伙
driving a car just like this.
开这种车救走了
You know,
我一想啊
you're the only one I know
我认识的人里面
who happen to drive
只有石小姐
the same model
恰好开这种车
and you just happen
而石小姐又恰好
to know Mrs. Ji,
跟我们抓的共产党
whom we arrested.
季太太有来往
It's my duty
职责所在
to verify this.
我必须来确认一下
I hope
那希望你回去
when you report back,
交差的时候
you'll let the others at the Secret Service know
告诉特务处其他人
to stop bothering me.
不要再来打扰我
Don't be upset, Ms. Shi.
别生气啊 石小姐
Maybe I can make it up to you
要不改天你有空
by inviting you out for a beer sometime?
我请你喝啤酒赔罪
I've always loved stargazing.
我很喜欢看星星
In my early days at Shanghai,
刚来上海那会儿
I used to
我没事儿经常
lie by the window and gaze at the stars.
趴在我家窗户边看星星
During my sea training,
海上训练的时候
I spent long periods lying on the deck, gazing into sky.
我会躺在甲板上看很久
Can you see more stars
海上是不是可以
at sea?
看到更多的星星
Yes,
对
like shooting stars.
群星闪耀
Do you know
那你知道
which one is the brightest?
最亮的是哪颗星吗
Sirius,
天狼星
that one there.
就是那颗
It's the brightest star in the night sky.
它是夜空中最亮的恒星
You can find it
沿着猎户座的腰带
by following the belt of Orion.
就能找到它
Lying on the deck,
我躺在甲板上
I watched it rise from the southeast
看到午夜后的几个小时
a few hours after midnight,
它从东南方升起
reaching the south by dawn.
凌晨时到达南方
Especially in
尤其是冬天
the winter months at dawn,
这几个月的黎明时分
it shines
它会在天上发出
brilliantly white.
耀眼的白光
In ancient Egypt,
在古埃及
people used Sirius
人们用天狼星
to predict the flooding of the Nile;
来预测尼罗河的洪灾
in ancient Greece,
在古希腊
it marked
人们用它
the dog days of summer;
来标记夏季的三伏天
and in the Southern Hemisphere,
在南半球
Polynesians
波利尼西亚人
used it to mark the winter.
用天狼星来标记冬天
I've heard
我听说
that when people sail across the ocean
人们在大洋上航行
for days and nights,
航行几天几夜
seeing only water
都只能看得见水
with no landmarks
没有地标
to tell them where they are
可以告诉他们在哪里
or where they are going,
或者要去向哪里
sailors observe
那个时候
the stars
人们就会仰望星空
because the stars
因为星星
can show them the way.
会指明方向
That's still true today.
其实现在也是如此
Enemies can jam
敌人可以干扰
mechanical detectors
机械探测仪
and disrupt compasses and chronometers,
可以破坏罗盘和天文钟
but they can't destroy the stars.
但他们不能摧毁星辰
Look,
你们看那些星星
some stars dim
有的暗了下去
and others brighten.
有的又亮了起来
Instead of the brightest star,
比起最亮的那颗星
I prefer watching
我更喜欢看
many stars shining.
现在这样的群星闪耀
[In the winter of 1936,]
民国二十五年冬
[the National Government in Nanjing]
南京国民政府
[arrested seven leaders of the NSO,]
以危害民国罪
[including Shen Junru,]
在上海逮捕了沈钧儒等
[on charges of undermining the Republic,]
七名救国会领袖
[known historically as the "Seven Gentlemen Incident."]
史称七君子事件
[This arrest sparked]
此事引发了
[outrage across all sectors of society,]
全国各界人士的愤慨
[leading to]
在随后的几周
[extensive protests]
便展开了
[and rescue efforts]
声势浩大的抗议
[in the following weeks,]
和营救活动
[which further unified]
无数中华儿女的
[the patriotic fervor]
抗日热情
[of countless Chinese citizens]
也因此次事件
[against the Japanese aggression.]
凝聚了起来
[Amid such circumstances,]
在如此背景之下
[the Shanghai police's collusion with the Japanese forces]
上海警方与日本军方
[in smuggling military supplies]
勾结走私军需品一事
[was also exposed by the NSO.]
也被救国会一并曝出
Quiet down!
闭嘴
Get them all out of here!
全轰走 轰走
Show yourself!
你出来
Everyone, quiet!
都闭嘴 闭嘴
Get them out!
全给我轰走
Hand over Feng!
让姓冯的出来
Drive them away!
全轰走 轰走
[Feng, show yourself!]
让冯科长出来
[Smuggling tung oil to the Japanese,]
走私桐油 给日本人
[are you trying to be]
他这是要当
[a lapdog for the Japanese?]
日本人的走狗吗
[Quiet!]
都闭嘴
[We demand answers!]
给百姓一个交代
[Everyone, calm down!]
都给我闭嘴
Feng Sir,
科长
this is bad!
出大事儿了
The place is swarming
现在外面全是
with reporters looking for you!
找你的记者
For me?
找我
Yes.
是
What do they want with me?
找我干什么
They want an interview.
说是要采访
That Peng
那个姓彭的记者
yesterday at the Guotai Theatre
昨天在国泰大剧院
spilled everything about you
把您和谭副局长的事儿
and Deputy Director Tan,
全都抖出来
especially about you!
特别是您
He claimed
说
the kidnapping was under your orders
被绑架是您指使的
and that the smuggling is also connected to you.
还说走私也跟您有关系
Nonsense!
胡说八道
What does that
这些事儿
have to do with me?
跟我有什么关系
I don't know either!
我也不知道
But now everyone's
现在全部都
asking about it!
在问这件事儿
Drive them away!
赶走
All of them!
全部赶走
Well...
这
I...
我
What are you waiting for?
愣着干什么
Drive them away!
赶走
Yes, Sir!
是
[Disperse!]
散了
[Everyone disperse!]
都散了
[Break it up!]
都给我散了
[Go away!]
散开
Sorry, Feng Sir.
对不起 冯科长
What happened
昨天国泰大剧院
at the Guotai Theatre yesterday?
怎么回事
We thought it was just
本以为只是个
a fan meeting with a playwright,
剧作家影迷见面会
nothing significant,
没人在意
but unexpectedly,
可没想到
that journalist Peng
那个姓彭的记者
suddenly appeared
突然冒了出来
and started making bold statements.
在剧院大放厥词
He also brought a dozen
他还带去了十几个
of his journalist colleagues,
报界的同行
and I just found out
我也刚刚查明
that the playwright
那个剧作家
is actually a leftist.
原来是个左翼分子
So, I suspect
所以我怀疑
that the CPC
这背后
might be
很有可能
plotting something behind the scenes.
是共产党在暗中谋划
Right now, I'm only concerned
我现在只关心
about the port clearance permits.
出港许可证的问题
Two shipments
明天那两车货
are due at Shiliupu Wharf tomorrow.
就要到十六铺码头了
With this incident,
发生这种事
are the permits still releasable?
许可证没问题吧
Rest assured,
您放心
Mr. Gao of the Shanghai Customs District Anti-smuggling Section
江海关缉私科的高科长
has promised me
答应过我
the permits
许可证
will be issued on time.
一定能按时发下来
Deputy Director Tan,
谭副局长
for me,
对我来说
this isn't just about
这不仅仅是
whether a shipment
一船货能不能运到
can get to Nagasaki Port.
长崎港的问题
It's about whether this supply chain
而是这条供应链
can continue
还能不能够
to operate.
继续维持的问题
This matter affects
这件事关系到
the strategic plans of the Army Ministry
陆军省的布局
and, consequently, your...
也关系到谭副局长你的
career prospects.
前途
I understand.
我明白
I will
这事儿
personally oversee this
我一定亲自督办
and ensure your shipment
确保您的货
boards on schedule.
准时上船
Mr. Hua? There's a call for you.
华先生是吗 您电话
Hello?
喂
Feng Sir!
冯科长
Mr. Feng, you really can't go in!
冯科长你真的不能进去
I need to see the Deputy Director urgently.
我找副局长有急事儿
Deputy Director Tan specifically instructed...
谭副局长特意交代过
Feng Sir!
冯科长
Deputy Director,
副局长
have you heard
彭记者的事儿
about Peng's statement?
您听说了吧
He's now coming out
他现在跳出来
accusing me of kidnapping, murder,
说我绑架谋杀
and smuggling involvement.
还涉嫌走私
I was just helping you
我只是在中间
pick up and deliver things.
帮您取东西送东西
How could that be smuggling?
这怎么能是走私呢
You're well aware of all I've done.
您是知道的呀
Why the panic?
慌什么
The precinct entrance
现在分局门口
is swarming
堵的全是
with journalists demanding answers from me.
找我要说法的记者
What should I do?
我该怎么办
What do you want to do?
你想怎么办
Arrest the journalists,
把记者抓回来
keep an eye on the NSO people.
安排人看住救国会的人
We need to shut them up.
得把他们的嘴堵上啊
What do you think
那您觉得
we should do?
我们应该怎么办
Right now,
你现在啊
you don't need to do anything.
什么都不用做
Just go home and lie low.
先回家避避风头
I don't quite follow.
我没太明白您的意思
That means
就是
you're being suspended.
先停你的职
Suspended?
停职
Yes,
没错
We'll tell them that you're under investigation.
对外就说你在接受调查
Now that things have escalated to this point,
现在事情闹到了这一步
let them come at me
让他们有什么事儿啊
whatever they got.
就冲着我来
But even if I'm suspended,
可是就算停了我的职
the permits and manifests are still out there.
通行证跟货单还在外面
Will they really let me go?
他们能放过我吗
I've already suspended
我把我的爱将
my best men for investigation.
都已经停职查办了
What more do they want?
他们还想怎么样
Don't worry,
你放心
the suspension is just for a few days,
停职就几天的事儿
mainly
主要是想
to appease the public.
给外界一个交代
I've already discussed it
我跟里见先生
with Mr. Nakamura.
都已经说好了
Once this blows over,
等风头过去了
business will continue as usual,
生意照旧
and you
你啊
will be back
很快还是会
at my side soon enough.
回到我的身边
Leave it to me.
我来给你换
Tomorrow the shipment arrives
明天吴淞口那批货
at Wusong Port.
就要到码头了
It's our last chance
这是拦截新荣丸号
to intercept the Shinei Maru.
最后的机会
This could
这关系到
sever the smuggling route
能不能彻底斩断
once and for all.
这条走私线
They usually hand over
按照他们的老规矩
the permits and manifests
通行证和货单
to Feng Guangyun.
都会交到冯广云手上
Early tomorrow,
到时候一早
I'll follow Feng Guangyun
我去跟着冯广云
and see if I can
看看能不能找机会
retrieve those documents.
把这两样东西给拿回来
I'm going with you.
我跟你一起去
Why?
你去干吗
I can do it myself.
我自己去
That's an order.
这是命令
Orders?
还命令呢
Are you still my Captain?
你现在还是我队长吗
Am I still your crew?
我现在还是你的队员吗
I'm not your captain,
我确实不是你的队长
but your comrade
但从今天开始
from now on.
你就是我的同志了
What?
你说什么
Your application for
上级已经批准
joining the Party has been approved.
你的入党申请
Has his application
组织批准
been approved?
他的入党申请了
Yes.
对 批准了
He's been one
从今天开始
of our members.
他就是我们其中一员
And you're
从现在开始
a CPC member
你就真正地
from now on.
成为了一名共产党员
Really?
真的
I'm arranged
组织安排我
as your superior.
担任你的上线
My code name is 307.
我的代号是零三七
And we'll contact
从今以后
each other directly in the future.
由我直接和你联系
[Sir,]
老师
[do you]
您是觉得
[join the Party]
只有加入共产党
['cause you believe]
才能实现理想
[it's a necessary path]
所以您和他们
[to achieve the ideals?]
站在了一起
[Regardless of life or death,]
苟利社稷
[dedicate all to the country.]
死生以之
[I wanna become]
我想成为
[a man like Deng Mingyuan.]
像邓铭远先生一样的人
[We will]
我们必将成为
[do.]
像邓铭远先生那样的人
[May you]
愿你终有一天
[understand my choice one day.]
能够明白我的选择
The day finally comes.
我终于等到了这一天
Minmin.
珉敏
Go back home after dinner.
吃完饭你先回去吧
Pardon?
什么
You should
我说
go home after having dinner.
吃完饭你先回家吧
No.
不行
I must work
明天我必须
with you tomorrow.
跟你们一起行动
Feng Guangyun
之前冯广云
has long wanna hurt you.
就想对你们动手
What if
要是这次
he doesn't cooperate
他还是根本都不配合
and kills you
直接对你们下杀手
directly?
怎么办
That's why we asked you to go home.
所以才让你先回家
This is your task.
这是你的任务
Is my task to go home?
我的任务是回家吗
Don't you wanna be a person
你不是想成为石小姐
like Ms. Shi and Mrs. Ji?
季太太那样的人吗
Then you should learn to obey the order.
那就得先学会服从安排
But
可是
I just want to
我只是希望
do something
我可以做一些
to help you.
力所能及的事情
Not run away
而不是这时候
in times of crisis.
一个人逃走
I understand.
我明白
But we three can't
但我们三个人
take actions at the same time.
不能同时行动
When there is war,
如果这是打仗的话
people are sent to the front
我们是去前线
and rear lines.
而你镇守后方
This is the tactic.
这是策略
If any emergencies,
如果遇到什么特殊情况
you can help us
你可以随时地来
at any time.
援助我们
Do you understand?
明白吗
Moreover,
而且珉敏
since in Sanyang Fisheries
从三洋水产到这里
you haven't got back home for several days.
你已经好几天没回家了
Your family must
家里人没有你的消息
worry about you.
他们一定急坏了
How can you perform
你不解决好家里的事儿
the next tasks
怎么执行
before handling your own business?
接下来的任务呢
Chen Hao's right.
听陈浩的
I'll send you back after dinner.
吃完饭我先送你回去
But you're...
可是你的身体
No worries.
我知道
I've almost
你放心吧
recovered.
我已经恢复得差不多
And,
再说
Yuansheng is by my side.
还有向远生呢
Go back home
你先回去
to make your family feel at ease.
好好休息 报个平安
We'll meet you
我们执行完任务
when we finish the task.
第一时间跟你会合
OK.
好
I'll do it,
那我先回家
and prepare tasty food,
我让爸爸准备好吃的菜
including what you like most,
还有你喜欢的菜泡饭
waiting for your back.
等你们回来
Captain,
队长
is it called
这是不是就叫做
a victory meeting?
胜利会师
Yes.
对
Have a dinner.
吃饭吧
[Dad.]
爸
[Dinner is ready.]
吃饭了
I'm coming.
来了
What food do you cook?
今天吃什么好吃的
Courgette.
西葫芦
It's good.
这个也好
Help me.
来 给我盛饭
Dad.
爸
Minmin
三天了
disappeared for three days.
姐一点消息都没有
We can't find her anywhere.
怎么找都找不到
Why don't you worry?
这饭您吃得下去
It's not salty.
一点儿都不咸
Dad,
不是 爸
you're right to stop her
姐上次出警被伤成那样
after she's seriously injured last time.
您不让她当警察是对的
[The Fourth Station was disbanded,]
但是现在四所没了
[she stays]
她还整天
[with Chen Hao all day.]
跟着陈浩他们在一起
[He's wanted through the city.]
陈浩现在全城通缉
Don't you worry about her?
你就不怕姐出事儿吗
Have your dinner.
吃饭
It tastes good.
烧得好
Well, dad,
那什么 爸
I need
你先吃
some fresh air outside.
我去透口气
Go back
赶紧吃
soon.
别凉了
Minmin.
珉敏
Dad.
爸
Minmin is back!
爸 珉敏回来了 爸
Minmin.
姐
Are you injured?
受伤没有啊
What happened?
你受伤没有啊
Why
你怎么这么多天
so long?
都不回来
You okay?
有没有哪里受伤了
Any injuries?
有没有受伤啊
No.
没有
I'm fine.
我没事儿
I plan to
你再不回来
dismantle your bed,
我把你床都卸了
if you don't come back.
什么都不说
Where did you go?
不是 你去哪儿了
I can't have the meal.
我哪吃得下饭啊
We don't know nothing.
你怎么不跟家里说一声
Dad is waiting for you every day.
爸天天在门口等着你
Dad, Minmin is back!
爸 珉敏回来了 爸
Dad, here!
爸 姐回来了
Come in.
珉敏 进
Hurry up.
快进屋 进屋
Good.
不错
Dad,
爸爸
don't be angry.
您别生气了
I've been back safely.
我这不是好好回来了吗
I went on a trip
我这段时间
with Captain Chen
就是跟陈队长
and
还有向远生
Xiang Yuansheng.
一起出去玩儿了一趟
We went to the suburbs.
他们带我去了郊外
And they took a good care of me.
把我照顾得特别特别好
We...
我们一起
Sorry, dad.
对不起 爸爸
I made you feel worried again.
我又让你们担心了
Minmin.
珉敏
I can guess
你不用说
how you spent
我都能猜到
these days.
你这几天是怎么过的
I was furious
受伤之后
that you're seriously injured.
爸爸是很气愤
But I'm more afraid that
但是爸爸更多的是害怕
you can't wake up anymore.
害怕你再也醒不过来了
You should understand
你要知道
that
天祥
the three
你
of you
还有勤芹
mean everything
你们三个
to me.
是爸爸的一切
Did you remember what you'd said
你还记得你受伤之后
when you got injured last time?
跟我说的话吗
Yes.
记得
I said that
我跟爸爸说
I would remember your words.
我一定会记住爸爸的话
You told me that
爸爸告诉我
if
如果
I couldn't protect myself,
我没有能力保护好自己
then I couldn't protect others.
就没有能力保护好别人
Can you protect yourself now?
你现在有能力吗
Dad.
爸爸
I'm not sure
我不确定
I have the confidence
我是不是有十足的把握
to protect myself
可以保护好自己
or
我也不确定
anyone
我是不是
else.
可以去保护好别人
But I've learned a lot
可是这些天
these days,
我学到了很多
which has made me
也思考了很多
realize that there are many things
我觉得有一些事情
that I have to do.
是不得不去做的
I thought
我以前以为
if I worked hard to
只要足够努力
protect my family,
保护好自己的家人
I'd have a better life.
就可以好好地生活
But later,
但后来
I find a better life
我发现好好地生活
can't bring me
并不能给我带来
real happiness.
十足的快乐和开心
We can't only live a happy life ourselves.
人活着不能只为了自己
Dad.
爸爸
I've felt
这些天
the spirit of dedication
我从陈队长
from people
向远生
like Captain Chen,
还有一些新朋友身上
Xiang Yuansheng
看到了一种精神
and
那就是
other new friends.
为他人奉献
They're
爸爸
taking me to do
他们带着我
something meaningful
每一天都在做
every day.
有意义的事情
I
而且
can feel
我看到他们
that they can sacrifice
真的可以为了理想
everything for their ideals.
牺牲自己的一切
It has made me
我跟他们在一起
feel empowered
我觉得每一天都很充实
and fulfilled every day.
我觉得浑身充满了力量
Dad,
爸爸
the Captain
我问过队长
told me
队长跟我说
that is
这就是
the power of belief.
信仰的力量
I should
我想
learn from them
我也要向他们学习
to use faith
可以为了理想
as support
奉献自己的一切
and devote myself
我也想像他们一样
to the ideals.
成为有信仰的人
Let me
你让爸爸
carry you up.
驮驮
C'mon.
来
Take care, dad.
爸爸 你小心点儿
I'm heavy.
我可沉了
Actually,
真的长大了
[We're coming.]
来了 来了
Have a sit.
快坐下
I'm not that old.
没那么大年纪
Right.
对对对
Press it.
就 就是按那个
Wait.
你等一下
Change the light.
我把这个灯弄一下啊
OK.
好嘞
Press it, right?
就按这个是吧
Yes.
对对对
Close it.
闭上 闭上
OK.
好
Hurry up.
哥 你快点儿
I'm ready.
来来来
Ready?
好 来 准备了啊
Make sure everyone is in the picture.
把人放框里啊
OK, smile.
好 来笑一笑
Ready.
来 预备
Three,
来
two, one, go!
一 二 三
[One more time.]
好 再来一个啊
[Three,]
来
[two, one, go!]
一 二 三
[Where should we send]
明天拿到证据
[the evidence to tomorrow?]
送哪儿啊
Back here.
就送回这儿
Someone will
有人接应
contact the newspaper office
再由她送到报社
where printing will be done
报社每天下午一点
at 1 p.m. every day.
定版印刷
The organization wanna make it aired
组织想赶在明天晚报上
on the evening paper.
曝光证据
So, we must
所以我们必须
get it earlier.
更早地拿到证据
and send it back.
把它送回来
OK.
好
No matter
明天中途
what happens tomorrow,
无论发生什么事儿
take the evidence back.
你只管把证据拿回来
We'll meet here.
我们在这里会合
Both of us and the
明天我们两个人
two certificates
两张证
must be back here safely.
一定都会回到这儿
Feng Sir.
科长
It's
哥
the notice
这是上面
of suspension.
发下来的停职通知
You need to sign.
需要您签字儿
I'm sorry for that.
我也没有办法
Wang Yong,
王永
it's temporary,
我停职只是暂时的
used to silence the reporters.
为了堵住那帮记者的嘴
Indeed.
是
I'll be back soon.
过不了多久我就回来了
Don't be nervous.
别紧张
And
还有
tell others
你跟兄弟们说
to be careful.
注意点儿
Don't make remarks.
别在外边瞎说
You understand?
明白
I got you.
明白 哥
All of us
我和兄弟们
will wait for you.
都等着您回来
Can you go check if my police ID
我警员证好像落车里了
is in the car?
你帮我看一眼
OK.
好
Stop watching.
都别看了
Don't stay here.
散了
[Why isn't Mr. Feng waiting here]
以前都是冯科长来拿
[for picking up like before?]
今天他怎么没来啊
It's not your business.
不该问的话别问
Put it here.
东西放这儿就行了
Mr. Feng,
冯哥
why are you here?
您怎么来了呀
Give me the pass.
把通行证给我
I called you Mr. Feng
叫你一声冯哥
because of the relationship.
是给你之前的情分
Well.
怎么
Why not wear the uniform?
怎么没穿警服呢
Since you're no longer an officer,
你说你也不是冯科长了
I cannot
我自然不能
give you such an important thing.
把这么重要的东西给你
You said that I was your dog.
你还说我像条狗一样
C'mon,
其实最大的狗
you're the real dog!
那就是你